Animation carries information.
It shows progress, confirms an outcome,
and explains where focus moved.
But reduced-motion implementations often remove
the animation—and the meaning with it.
StillMeaning asks: what disappears when motion disappears?
Then it reduces motion, not meaning.
This continuous shimmer says an upload is active.
Turn it off and the bar becomes static:
is it moving, stalled, or complete?
StillMeaning exposes that ambiguity, then replaces the moving cue
with status text, an exact value, and real progress-bar semantics.
Here, scale, rotation, and path drawing
communicate success.
Removing them leaves an unlabeled icon.
StillMeaning makes the result persistent:
Changes saved, synchronization detail,
and a polite status announcement—without relying
on motion or color alone.
This slide communicates movement into a deeper level.
Remove it and the content swaps without explanation—
and keyboard focus remains behind.
StillMeaning names the destination, preserves hierarchy,
moves focus logically, and replaces travel with a short fade.
StillMeaning does more than give advice.
It generates an inspectable implementation,
shows the before-and-after diff,
explains the transformation,
and lets developers copy it.
Generated code remains untrusted text;
the workbench never executes it.
GPT-5.6 does the core reasoning.
It identifies each motion-carried signal
and predicts what becomes lost or ambiguous,
selects replacement cues, generates code,
and links every cue to structured validation evidence.
The server adds strict schema validation, bounded input,
a timeout, and a server-only key.
Provenance always distinguishes live GPT-5.6
from the demo fallback shown here.
Codex helped audit, design, implement, test, debug, deploy,
and document the project in one primary development session.
StillMeaning: reduce motion, not meaning.